<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news.atom"/>
  <title>BatteryClerk.ca - News</title>
  <updated>2021-08-10T11:30:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>BatteryClerk.ca</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/property-management-replacement-battery-planning</id>
    <published>2021-08-10T11:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-11T11:06:15-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/property-management-replacement-battery-planning"/>
    <title>Property Management Replacement Battery Planning</title>
    <author>
      <name>Aric Shelko</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<span>Managing properties and facilities means taking care of a lot of moving parts, people and situations. Having a replacement battery plan in place is important and will help to ensure that you won't get stranded in an emergency.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/property-management-replacement-battery-planning">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Property Managers typically have a lot on their plates, especially if they’re managing multiple properties or large and commercial ones, so it makes sense to keep your tenants happy as well as minimize any potential issues. Usually Property Managers have a checklist that they’ll run weekly or monthly and will include things like air filters, temperature settings, vermin and general structural checks but there are some items where having direct access to a battery manufacturer can ease potential headaches and keep costs down significantly.</p>
<p>A couple of items on the checklist can be critical in maintaining a safe building environment.</p>
<p><strong><span>Smoke Alarms and CO Detectors</span></strong> - are definitely an essential part of the checklist. Some tenants will remove them completely rather than letting you know that the battery is low or there’s an issue with it. Many larger systems rely on backup batteries in case power is compromised so keeping them updated is essential.</p>
<p><a href="/collections/security-system-batteries" title="Security system replacement batteries"><strong>Security systems</strong></a> offer an important level of safety for tenants and their equipment so the last thing you want is to have one malfunctioning or not working because your backup battery is low. Keep a bunch handy.</p>
<p><a href="/collections/generator-batteries" title="Generator batteries"><strong>Generators</strong></a> – for buildings like hospitals, a working generator is literally a matter of life and death but even for laboratories or catering facilities where thousands of dollars of food requires refrigeration, having a functional generator in the building is essential. Test your generator regularly and for those with a starter battery, make sure that battery works.</p>
<p><strong>Medical Equipment</strong> – if you manage a property that contains a lot of <a href="/collections/medical-batteries" title="medical equipment batteries">medical equipment</a> like a hospital or urgent care facility, some of it needs to be on at all times. A lot of the mobile equipment like wheelchairs and mobility scooters are battery powered so keeping them charged and having a fresh set of replacements is a key item to add to your checklist.</p>
<p>Managing properties and facilities means taking care of a lot of moving parts, people and situations. Those in more challenging locations where earthquakes, hurricanes and winter storms occur have even more challenging situations to consider. Having a plan in place is important and most will rely on a checklist for maintaining a sound environment.</p>
<p>At BatteryClerk we take our role in Property and Facility Managers tasks very seriously.</p>
<ol>
<li>We provide a platform for them to access our website at <a href="/pages/wholesale-batteries" title="Whole batteries page">wholesale rates</a> so cost savings are right there for them to see.</li>
<li>We take customer service very seriously. If you have questions, we’re there to answer. If there is an issue, we’ll review immediately.</li>
</ol>
<p>The majority of our clients who are <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/pages/replacement-batteries-for-facility-managers" title="replacement batteries for property managers">property and facility managers</a> have wholesale accounts which gives them even more competitive prices directly through our website but allows for the benefit of ordering in bulk which not only ensures that equipment is ready to go but there’s a backup replacement battery handy. And if that backup isn’t there, quick (and free) delivery is just a click or call away.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/our-guide-to-replacing-batteries-in-your-personal-watercraft</id>
    <published>2021-07-27T11:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-28T11:15:55-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/our-guide-to-replacing-batteries-in-your-personal-watercraft"/>
    <title>Our Guide to PWC Replacement Batteries in your Personal Watercraft</title>
    <author>
      <name>Aric Shelko</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span>Whether for work or play, Personal Watercraft can be a great vehicle around the waterways. Keeping your battery in top working order ensures that your watercraft continues to operate. Here's our guide to making sure you get out on the water and minimize the potential for getting stranded.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/our-guide-to-replacing-batteries-in-your-personal-watercraft">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Personal Watercraft can provide a lot of fun activities around the waterways with friends or family. In Canada, the window for using PWC's can be pretty short so getting the most out of that time is essential. Since the early 70’s when Kawasaki came out with their <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/personal-watercraft-batteries/brand_kawasaki-jet-ski" title="jet ski replacement batteries">Jet Ski brand</a>, people have been using personal watercraft for pleasure and also for work in increasing numbers with a number of other manufacturers including Yamaha and Bombardier with their <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/personal-watercraft-batteries/brand_sea-doo" title="Sea-Doo replacement batteries">Sea-Doo</a> helping to contribute to that popularity.</p>
<p>Whether on flat water, ocean or in the waves, PWC’s are a versatile vehicle and as a result have been increasingly used in situations where small motorboats have difficulties like for surf rescue, Coast Guard and Navy, fishing and even for racing.</p>
<p>Increased popularity can also increase its dangers with injuries and deaths occurring. Guidelines and laws have been implemented in many areas to minimize these issues, some waterways banning them completely. Another hazard can be due to mechanical issues which may result in falls, collisions or becoming lost and stranded as a result of engine failure or starting issues. A dead or low battery can certainly leave you in an unenviable position of not being able to return to your destination.</p>
<h3>About the PWC Battery</h3>
<p>A PWC battery should last around 3-5 years but there can be other factors that will reduce that number which is usually to do with how you maintain it. Typically if you’re not using it, you want to keep it charged or intermittently charge your battery especially during winter. Follow the charging directions as they can vary plus you also want to be careful not to overcharge the battery. The last thing you want when you go for your first run of the season is to hear the dreaded clicking sound and then have to figure out where to recharge it. <strong>Do not use your car battery</strong>, it will overcharge your system and fry your electronics so make sure to use your battery charger or a smart battery charger. Solar battery chargers can also be useful in more portable situations where you may not have access to power or are close to water.</p>
<p>Also keep in mind that unlike car batteries, your PWC battery won’t charge when you use it so if it keeps having issues, there may be something more significant, perhaps a broken charger, sulfating, bad cables or just an old battery especially if it’s been around 3 years.</p>
<h3>Finding a Replacement PWC Battery</h3>
<p>The best battery you can get for your PWC is an AGM Battery. These can handle a lot more abuse than the regular lead acid batteries. They’re also ready to go so you don’t need to have to think about filling it or charging it.</p>
<p>You’ll need to figure out the best replacement option. Often you’ll see a model number on that actual battery. Sometimes you can search by the actual watercraft model and that will help to direct your search. If you <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/personal-watercraft-batteries" title="Personal Watercraft batteries">search on batteryclerk.ca</a> for Kawasaki JH750 for example you’ll be presented with several options, which you can refine by year and specific model.</p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0005/3175/9163/files/Screen_Shot_2019-03-27_at_2.23.23_PM_large.png?v=1554211669" alt="search for kawasaki jh750 replacement battery"></p>
<p>Keeping your PWC running is top priority especially during warmer weather months and considering the short summers in Canada. Make sure to check your batteries so you can get going as soon as you hit the water.</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7StRrv9Y6wQ" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/marine-boat-replacement-batteries</id>
    <published>2021-07-07T10:55:37-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-07T12:36:14-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/marine-boat-replacement-batteries"/>
    <title>Marine &amp; Boat Replacement Batteries</title>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Fleming</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span>AJC marine and boat batteries are designed specifically for boats and RV’s. Marine batteries are able to provide the right power where you need it. Here are a few tips to look for when on the hunt for a replacement battery.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/marine-boat-replacement-batteries">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>For some lovers of the great outdoors, having equipment that enhances our experiences can be a big part of it. Whether it be an RV or travel trailer and getting on the open road or a boat or pontoon for fishing and other recreational activities, your gear needs the right replacement batteries to run when you need it. Designed specifically for boats and RV’s, <a href="https://ajcbattery.com/products/marine-boat-batteries/" title="marine &amp; boat replacement batteries">AJC marine batteries</a> are able to provide the right power where you need it.</p>
<h3>
<strong>What options are available?</strong>  </h3>
<p><strong>Starting Batteries</strong> – are designed to provide a quick burst of power for starting an RV or a large boat. They need to be powerful and withstand a lot of vibrations. Typically they will sit flat but depending on the makeup of the engine, especially on boats, they may need to be placed at an angle.</p>
<p><strong>Deep Cycle batteries</strong> – these are designed to run for longer periods of time before requiring a charge. Typically they’ll be used to power accessories like lights on boats and RV’s, allow you to open canopies, run TV’s or microwaves or other lower powered electrical items while the engine is off. They’re also useful for powering trolling motors on smaller watercraft.</p>
<p><strong>Dual Purpose Batteries</strong> – will do a little bit of both starting and deep cycling but it’s important to note that typically does both moderately. Typically used for starting smaller boats or generators and run time is a little shorter.</p>
<h3>A Few Things to Look For</h3>
<ol>
<li>For outdoor equipment we really need to accentuate the fact that RV, <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/pages/marine-boat-replacement-battery" title="Marine &amp; Boat Replacement Battery Tips">Marine &amp; Boat replacement batteries</a> need to be able to handle some extreme conditions including bumps and salt water and some need to be able to sit sideways or upside down so finding a replacement battery that can take some abuse and fit appropriately in the given are is key so check the dimensions.</li>
<li>It’s best to keep batteries on a low charge (by way of a trickle charger) when not in use. Keeping it active will extend its lifespan. Alternatively, before off-season storage make sure to completely disconnect the terminals so that the batteries won’t get drawn down</li>
<li>A battery has a limited shelf life and while we suggest 3-5 years, in reality for boats and RV’s we typically hear 2 years being a more realistic timeframe. Some can be identified pretty easily if it cuts out without warning or starts much slower. A multimeter is a useful tool for testing and some boating and RV equipment also comes with internal checks.</li>
<li>We suggest sticking with a single battery type and for us AGM is preferred given its price point, low maintenance requirement, lifespan and ability to handle extreme conditions.</li>
</ol>
<h3>Some additional things to consider:</h3>
<p><strong>Cranking Amps</strong> (CCA) – for RV and Marine they are more likely to be referred as MCA’s (marine cranking amps) which refers to the level of amps the unit can push for 30 seconds at 32 degrees Fahrenheit. Cold temperatures can significantly impact the battery performance.</p>
 
<p><strong>Amp Hours</strong> – generally are the measurement of the battery’s longevity and its ability to sustain a discharge above 10.5 volts in 80 degree weather.</p>
<p>Marine and RV equipment have some very specific requirements so when looking for a replacement battery, Marine batteries have an identifier where M is included after the Group number so if you’re looking for a battery in the BCI Group Number 31, labeling typically incorporates that as Group 31M.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0005/3175/9163/files/rv-marine.jpg?v=1617648999" alt="rv marine battery"></p>
<p>So grab a replacement battery or a backup and go and enjoy your boat or RV without worrying about whether your battery will last. Check out our current selection at <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/marine-and-boat-batteries" title="Marine &amp; Boat Replacement Batteries">https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/marine-and-boat-batteries</a></p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tDjC83Wr8FU" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/atv-utv-battery-maintenance</id>
    <published>2021-06-23T12:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-24T12:12:22-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/atv-utv-battery-maintenance"/>
    <title>ATV/UTV Replacement Battery Maintenance</title>
    <author>
      <name>Aric Shelko</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Whether you ride an ATV or UTV, you need to have the battery in prime condition to get your engine started. Check out these ATV/UTV battery maintenance tips so your battery will start the engine when you are ready to ride.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/atv-utv-battery-maintenance">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><strong>What's the difference between ATV and UTV?</strong></p>
<p>Both vehicles have something in common. They are for riding outdoors and they have four wheels. Many manufacturers make both ATVs and UTVs.</p>
<p>ATV stands for All Terrain Vehicle. The rider steers with handlebars for a cool recreational ride. Some ATVs are big enough for two people but most are one passenger vehicles.</p>
<p>UTV is for Utility Task Vehicle or Utility Terrain Vehicle. They tend to be larger and heavier than ATVs and can accommodate 2 to up to 4 people. They have steering wheels instead of handle bars and seats, instead of saddles. Recently they have started to shed their image of being farm work vehicles, as some manufacturers are creating high powered UTVs to appeal to families on the go!</p>
<p><strong>Maintain the battery</strong></p>
<p>Regardless of your choice of ride, you need to have the battery in prime condition to get your engine started. If you are a seasonal rider, you will need to maintain the battery in the off season, so it is capable of starting the engine when you are ready to ride. Batteries will discharge with lack of use, and if allowed to discharge too far, it may not re-charge. Then you need to purchase a new one!</p>
<p>When you are ready to put the vehicle in storage for the off season, you want to get a <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/battery-chargers-and-adapters">trickle battery charger</a> and hook it up. This will keep the battery charged and prolong its useful life. Some batteries are hard to reach in the vehicle and you may need to install a quick disconnect cable to allow you to hook up the charger without removing the battery from your vehicle. Check your manual for ways to accomplish this, as each manufacturer lays things out a bit differently.</p>
<p>Some things that don't work for charging the battery are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Starting the ATV or UTV every so often and turning it off. You use more power than you replace by doing this.</li>
<li>Starting the vehicle and idling, as getting a significant charge will take a very long time.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>When it's time to replace the battery</strong></p>
<p>Even with the right care, you will eventually need to replace your <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/atv-batteries">atv/utv battery</a>. Get a high quality replacement battery. Modern ATVs and UTVs can use the newer technology AGM (absorbed glass mat) batteries. These are maintenance free and sealed to prevent leaks. They can also be installed in any orientation if you happen to have a cramped battery compartment.</p>
<p>BatteryClerk.ca has quality replacement batteries for <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/atv-batteries/brand_polaris">most brands of ATVs and UTVs</a> in stock and ready to ship. Order online or give us a call and we will have you back on the dirt roads having fun!</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CvJYZ-4XlZU" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/what-is-the-ajc-battery-story</id>
    <published>2021-06-01T10:41:35-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-01T10:41:36-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/what-is-the-ajc-battery-story"/>
    <title>What is the AJC Battery Story?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Aric Shelko</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>In 2010, AJC founder Aric Shelko noticed he was using a lot of batteries around the house and for his business and most replacement batteries were very expensive, sometimes just as expensive as the item it was supposed to power. This didn’t make sense to him. So, he started looking a little deeper. This deeper look took him to explore different battery types and styles and had him really going down the rabbit hole of experimentation with quality and performance. </p>
<p>One of his first discoveries was that some of those expensive batteries were as much as the equipment they are supposed to power and he saw very little difference in performance vs the cheaper variations. Being able to save money without losing quality was important. </p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0005/3175/9163/files/battery-group-white.jpg?v=1621430553" alt="" width="558" height="420"></p>
<p>An issue with the cheaper replacement batteries for Aric was consistency in quality. While most of them performed well, there were some that did not and hinted at a low quality control process. The other issue he found was delivery times. Even though he was saving money and didn’t mind waiting a little longer, some wait times were extreme. 3 and 4 weeks was just too long to have to wait. </p>
<p>After spending some time researching, he saw an opportunity and decided to look a little closer at the battery manufacturing process. </p>
<p>Something he found interesting was that these batteries were predominately made in the same factories, and it seemed that the labels were a large factor dictating the ultimate pricing. Another factor influencing the pricing was the QA process. Having staff available to test every battery certainly adds to the cost and some would cut corners in this area. It certainly seemed to be a very important part of the process. The results of his research gave Aric enough data to decide to start his own replacement battery brand that combined affordability, quality and performance.</p>
<p>In 2012 Aric created the <a href="https://www.ajcbattery.com" title="AJC brand battery website">AJC battery brand</a>. Its mission was quite simply to “offer quality batteries at affordable prices”. He was able to manufacture batteries that provided the quality he needed at the right price. He was able to ensure that no corners were cut during the QA process. He was able to get the shipping process down to be able to offer same day shipping. He put systems in place to be able to support customer services, created an ecommerce website to sell direct to consumers all with the goal of keeping pricing as low as possible for consumers. It meant being smart with partnerships. The main key though, was relying on the quality of the product. Having satisfied customers meant return order and strong word of mouth which all allowed Aric to keep pricing down. </p>
<p>AJC Battery has grown every year since those early days and has increased their range of batteries to include <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/ajc-powersports-batteries" title="powersports replacement batteries">Powersports</a> and <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/dual-purpose-starting-and-deep-cycle-marine-and-boat-batteries" title="marine replacement batteries">Marine batteries</a> and can now accommodate more than tens of thousands of products for all of the leading brands. While there have been plenty of challenges along the way, the ultimate goal continues to provide quality batteries at affordable prices. Visit <a href="http://www.ajcbattery.com">www.ajcbattery.com</a> and <a href="https://batteryclerk.com" title="BatteryClerk website">batteryclerk.ca</a></p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dcA5v6S-zw8" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/dual-purpose-replacement-batteries</id>
    <published>2021-04-22T14:10:08-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-22T14:10:09-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/dual-purpose-replacement-batteries"/>
    <title>Dual Purpose Replacement Batteries</title>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Fleming</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span>What is a dual purpose battery and when is it best to use one? We break down the specifics and include a few things to look for when searching for a replacement dual purpose battery.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/dual-purpose-replacement-batteries">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>We briefly looked at Dual Purpose batteries in our <a href="https://batteryclerk.com/blogs/news/looking-for-rv-marine-replacement-batteries" title="RV &amp; Marine replacement batteries">RV &amp; Marine replacement battery post</a> recently and feel it’s important to get a little more detailed about these types of batteries. One of the biggest misconceptions that we hear is that it’s better to buy a dual purpose battery instead of a deep cycle or starting battery because it does the job of both, it takes up less space and it’s more cost-effective to buy one battery vs two. While there may be some truth in those points overall, it’s not entirely accurate.</p>
<p>Much like the jack-of-all-trades vs master-of-none, the dual purpose battery does ok in its deep cycle role but certainly its runtime will generally be nowhere near as good as a deep cycle battery. So too when comparing dual purpose with a starting battery, in fact there are plenty of occasions where a dual purpose battery won’t actually be able to start a vehicle.</p>
<p>Typically, deep cycle batteries are built to withstand a lot of discharges and recharges but dual purpose batteries don’t do well beyond 50% of usable capacity and also don’t stand up as well in tough conditions, many can be especially prone to overheating especially when used for long periods of time. So these alone should be considerations. If you only take short boat trips on a smaller vessel, the dual purpose may be all you need. A bigger boat on longer trips would probably not be best for a dual purpose battery.</p>
<p>As with all replacement batteries, there are a few key things to look for when selecting a dual purpose replacement battery.</p>
<p><strong>Volts</strong> – typically dual purpose batteries are all 12V</p>
<p><strong>CCA or MCA</strong>– the cold cranking amps (cca) or marine cranking amps (mca) measurement tells you how many amps will be delivered to the engine in cold temperatures. They are both measured at 0 degrees, the difference between the two is that cca is Fahrenheit and mca is Celsius. Essentially that equates to 0℉ and 32℉. They range from 300 to over 1200.</p>
<p><strong>Amp Hours (Ah)</strong> – amp hours give a general idea of the time that the battery can provide power for. Calculating how long your battery will power something for is fairly complex but in general, the bigger the number, the longer the runtime.</p>
<p><strong>Group Number</strong> – the group number for dual purpose batteries reflects the physical size of the casing. Typically this will include BCI (Battery Council International) and include a number plus M. That number like <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/bci-group-31-batteries" title="BCI 31M batteries">BCI 31M</a> will be 13” x 6-13/16” x 9-7/16”.</p>
<p><strong>Reserve Capacity (RC)</strong> – similar to Ah in that it’s a way to measure run time, reserve capacity or reserve minutes provide a rating for the number of minutes a battery can sustain a discharge of 25 amps before it will run out. Dual purpose batteries shouldn’t discharge lower that 50% so a reserve capacity of 120 could handle a load for an hour (60 minutes).</p>
<p><a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/dual-purpose-starting-and-deep-cycle-marine-and-boat-batteries">Dual purpose batteries</a> are typically used in boats and RV’s because they both need a battery that provides a high powered charge that helps to start an engine or generator and also provide a lower level discharge to power accessories like lighting, GPS, fish finders, TV’s, trolling motors and the like. Still, before you rush out and look to consolidate your starting and deep cycle batteries, it’s important to do your research to determine if it’s a good fit for your needs as there are some things that a dual purpose battery can’t do or certainly can’t do as well as a specialist battery.</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YNb_P0F4988" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/batteryclerk-donates-replacement-batteries-to-gift-of-mobility-giveaway</id>
    <published>2020-12-23T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-23T10:12:17-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/batteryclerk-donates-replacement-batteries-to-gift-of-mobility-giveaway"/>
    <title>BatteryClerk Donates Replacement Batteries to Gift Of Mobility Giveaway</title>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Fleming</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span>The Gift of Mobility Program generously gives away refurbished mobility scooters to those who really need them. After learning about the program and the need for replacement batteries, BatteryClerk reached out and offered to supply them with the required batteries.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/batteryclerk-donates-replacement-batteries-to-gift-of-mobility-giveaway">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">
<p>After recently learning of a program aimed at providing refurbished mobility scooters to those who can’t afford them, BatteryClerk has donated a selection of mobility scooter replacement batteries to the program. With scooters ranging in price from $4,000 to $40,000, many with disabilities and mobility issues are simply unable to afford them and as a result struggle to move around freely.</p>
<p>BatteryClerk CEO Aric Shelko says “we heard about the program and could appreciate how beneficial it was to those in need. We take for granted the ability to get around easily but those with physical restrictions really rely on electric scooters and wheelchairs just to perform basic activities”</p>
<p>Mobility Scooters not only need to be mechanically sound but also need working batteries to provide power. The Gift of Mobility program repairs broken scooters to make them functional again and BatteryClerk has donated replacement batteries to provide the power to get them running. Since 2009 the AZ Pawn Gift of Mobility Program has been refurbishing unwanted scooters and giving them away during the holiday season to those who cannot afford them. To date, they have given away over 600 scooters.</p>
<p>According to the program founder Phil Pavone “I am a cancer survivor who knows firsthand what these chairs mean to people. For those who are disabled these are much more than just a chair…. These are a means of independence, a chance to do normal things.”</p>
<p>BatteryClerk spotted the<span> </span><a href="https://www.gofundme.com/giftofmobility/" target="_blank" title="Gift of Mobility" rel="noopener noreferrer">GoFundMe page</a><span> </span>at which talked about the need for scooter batteries. BatteryClerk has an extensive range of replacement batteries for most major brands of mobility scooters so it seemed to be a great fit. Shelko adds “it was a no-brainer for us. We saw an opportunity to contribute, so we have donated several compatible replacement batteries and look to continue that relationship.”</p>
<p>Those with unwanted scooters and wheelchairs around the Connecticut area are encouraged to send them to the program. Alternatively donations to the program can be made on their GoFundMe page.</p>
<p>BatteryClerk makes an effort to keep battery prices as low as possible to make it easier for mobility scooter users to find a replacement. Browse our<span> </span><a href="https://batteryclerk.com/collections/scooter-batteries" title="mobility scooter replacement batteries">Mobility Scooter replacement batteries</a><span> </span>to find your match.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/powersports-batteries-a-few-things-to-know</id>
    <published>2020-10-07T11:12:09-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-10-07T11:12:10-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/powersports-batteries-a-few-things-to-know"/>
    <title>Powersports Batteries: A Few Things to Know</title>
    <author>
      <name>Aric Shelko</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span>Powersport vehicles like motorcycles and ATV's are powered by a motor that requires a battery to start it. A well maintained battery will give you a longer life. Here are a few things to know about these types of batteries.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/powersports-batteries-a-few-things-to-know">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>The battery in your powersport vehicle is hardier than batteries for your kids Power Wheels, but it still wants some attention to keep it running at its peak efficiency. There are a variety of different powersport vehicles, including motorcycles, ATVs, snowmobiles and personal watercraft. These are all powered by a motor that requires a battery to start it.</p>
<p><strong>Powersports Battery Facts</strong></p>
<p>The battery you need for your powersport vehicle is different than the batteries that run a wheelchair or scooter. You need a battery with higher cold cranking amps or CCA. Cold cranking Amps correlates directly to <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/ajc-powersports-batteries">powersports battery</a> performance. The higher the CCA, the better the battery can start your vehicle. CCA is the current that the battery can output for thirty seconds at zero degrees Fahrenheit.</p>
<p>The type of <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/motorcycle-batteries">battery for powersport vehicles</a> is generically called a valve regulated lead acid (VRLA) battery. Some of the advantages of this battery type are that they:</p>
<ol>
<li>are sealed and won’t spill, so they are safer</li>
<li>can be mounted on their sides in addition to flat</li>
<li>are maintenance free</li>
<li>don’t emit fumes</li>
<li>are more resistant to vibration</li>
</ol>
<p>VRLA batteries come in two types:</p>
<ol>
<li>Gel Batteries</li>
<li>AGM (absorbed glass mat) batteries</li>
</ol>
<p>Gel batteries are the older of the two technologies, and they lose power more quickly than AGM batteries, especially in colder weather. They also tend to have a shorter life span.</p>
<p>AGM batteries are suited to colder temperatures and they are great for high current and high power uses. They offer the best starting power, are more durable, and just offer a better value for your money.</p>
<p><strong>Maintenance will help your battery last</strong></p>
<p>Take a good, long look at your battery every month. Make sure it has no cracks and isn’t leaking. Check the terminals, and clean them if they show signs of corrosion. Make sure the connectors are tight once a month or right after a spill. Loose connectors might mean your vehicle won’t start at all, or intermittently. Keep the battery charged, too. The old wives tale about letting a battery completely discharge before charging will only shorten the lifespan of your battery.</p>
<p>Even sitting idle between rides, the battery will slightly discharge. But when the vehicle sits idle for a month or more, you should invest in a quality trickle charger. A good trickle charger will be able to detect the charge level of your battery, and automatically adjust the amperage. It will slow as the battery reaches a full charge, saving your battery from over-charging, and keeping it ready to ride.       </p>
<p><strong>Replacing the Battery</strong></p>
<p>But even with care and attention, you will eventually need to replace the battery. With good care, the battery should last between 3 and 5 years. Motorcycles and ATVs typically require 12 volt batteries, but the battery needs to provide high power output to start your powersport vehicle. You need a higher cold cranking amp, or CCA, output. As your ride gets older, a higher CCA will allow you to continue to enjoy it. When it’s time for that <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/ajc-powersports-batteries">replacement powersports battery</a>, check out BatteryClerk for the right battery at the right price.</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rUB19OqXLu0" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/replacement-battery-tutorials-guides</id>
    <published>2020-09-29T11:10:14-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-09-29T11:10:15-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/replacement-battery-tutorials-guides"/>
    <title>Replacement Battery Tutorials &amp; Guides</title>
    <author>
      <name>Aric Shelko</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span>BatteryClerk has put together a decent collection of resources to help customers find answers to their questions. They have recently added a Tutorials &amp; Guides section that aims to provide more extensive information.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/replacement-battery-tutorials-guides">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>At BatteryClerk, we've been selling replacement batteries for a while now (since 2010) and have learned a lot about batteries during that time. While they may not be an exciting subject for many, batteries are an important part of our lives so we've tried to make it as easy as possible for our customers to find the best match for their equipment. We also feel it's important to offer some tips on best practices when replacing your batteries. We don't have all the answers but we try to get as close as possible.</p>
<p>As a result, we've spent a lot of time putting together a robust resources section that hopefully provides some answers to your questions. Our FAQ's section has been built out through the years based on some of our most popular questions ask in our online chat app and phone calls.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2867/7354/files/faq.jpg?v=1601391811" alt=""></p>
<p>In addition, we have a fairly robust set of infographics that are designed to help provide a step-by-step process for replacing batteries for most of the most popular products including motorcycles, UPS devices, alarms etc.  </p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2867/7354/files/infographics.jpg?v=1601391871" alt=""></p>
<p>We also have a solid <a href="https://batteryclerk.com/pages/videos" title="replacement battery videos">selection of videos</a> which are designed to be more informational than instructional but we're regularly adding content there so feel free to check back regularly.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2867/7354/files/videos.jpg?v=1601391911" alt=""></p>
<p>We've recently started to add some Tutorials &amp; Guides which covers some of the battery basics that may not be familiar to many. We're also looking to embrace some more specific information to help guide customers through the replacement battery buying and installing process. In doing so, we are hoping that there are more happy customers. An informed customer is generally better for us. Check out our latest replacement battery <a href="https://batteryclerk.com/pages/tutorials-guides">Tutorials &amp; Guides</a>.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2867/7354/files/vids.jpg?v=1601392127" alt=""></p>
<p>And if that's not enough for you, we're also happy to help out in real time if need be. Our online chat tool is available from 8am-9pm EST, our phone line is also available during these times plus we've got someone checking in to Facebook and Twitter on a regular basis so if there are any questions, we should be available to help find the answers.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/lawn-mower-and-lawn-tractor-replacement-batteries</id>
    <published>2020-09-18T11:48:53-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-09-18T13:39:03-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/lawn-mower-and-lawn-tractor-replacement-batteries"/>
    <title>Lawn Mower and Lawn Tractor Replacement Batteries</title>
    <author>
      <name>Aric Shelko</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span>Tractor mowers and electric mowers continue to increase in popularity as has the demand for replacement batteries. Whether you need a battery to start a gas powered mower or a battery that actually runs the mower, finding one that fits your needs is valuable. We offer some tips.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/lawn-mower-and-lawn-tractor-replacement-batteries">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Lawn care equipment has come a long way since the days when the only options were scythes or animals. In fact, the first recorded patent for a lawn mower was in 1830 and was described as “a superior alternative to the scythe” and was much like the push reel mowers we see today. In 1902 gas powered mowers were invented and really paved the way for increased lawn management throughout the world. In the US in particular, lawns were seen as a symbol and stability and prosperity.</p>
<p>Lawn mower equipment continued to expand to include self-propelled mowers, ride-on mowers, lawn tractors and electric lawn mowers. Electric lawn mowers have proven to be a big hit recently, particularly as lawn areas have shrunk to make way for bigger houses, more varied landscapes and in many places, smaller property sizes. While electric lawn mowers were invented in the 1930’s, they really didn’t catch on until the technology significantly improved in addition to the fact that users have become more environmentally conscious. These days battery-powered mowers can run up to 60 minutes, enough time for a yard around 1500 sq ft. and overall costs (especially operating costs) can be significantly lower.</p>
<p>For those with larger properties, lawn tractors have become an incredibly valuable addition, saving a great deal of time and energy. Tractor mowers run on gas but will use a battery (generally SLA) to start, much like a car while electric mowers use either lithium-ion or rechargeable SLA batteries.</p>
<h4>Things to Consider When Finding a Replacement Mower Battery</h4>
<p><strong>Volts</strong> – this measures the amount of current that is able to flow. Tractor Lawnmowers generally have 12V batteries while battery powered lawn mowers range between 18V and 120V. For these in general, the higher the voltage, the longer it will run.</p>
<p><strong>Amp Hours</strong> – this generally is a measure of how long the battery will run.</p>
<p><strong>Size</strong> – for a replacement battery a critical requirement will be that it fits in the space provided. There’s nothing worse than buying a replacement and it won’t fit. Generally, when looking on BatteryClerk.com, putting your model number should yield the exact replacement but it’s worth checking the dimensions listed on the item to double check.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0005/3175/9163/files/mower-replacement-batteries.jpg?v=1600443121" alt="" width="" height=""></p>
<p>Growth in <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/pages/tractor-and-lawn-mower-battery-replacement" title="Tractor and lawn mower battery infographic">electric mowers and tractor mowers</a> has significantly helped to improve the quality of equipment. As a potential 9-billion-dollar industry, it’s in the manufacturers best interests to fill this need that is being driven by convenience, environment and decreased lawn sizes. Batteries generally last 3-5 years and typically finding a replacement is easy and affordable. Sometimes owners will buy a backup battery and switch them out if their lawn mowing runs longer than usual. BatteryClerk has a large inventory of <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/lawn-mower-and-tractor-batteries" title="lawn mower and tractor batteries">replacement batteries for lawn mowers and lawn tractors</a> to make it easier for all to find your replacement battery.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/wholesale-batteries-for-sale</id>
    <published>2020-08-08T13:22:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-08-11T09:31:42-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/wholesale-batteries-for-sale"/>
    <title>Wholesale Battery Supplier Canada</title>
    <author>
      <name>Aric Shelko</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>At BatteryClerk, we welcome any and all bulk battery buyers and look forward to working with you to meet your replacement battery needs. Buying batteries wholesale can mean savings and benefits for you and your company.</p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/wholesale-batteries-for-sale">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>If you need batteries, a lot of batteries, you will be looking for a great price, quality batteries, and an easy, streamlined process for procuring them all in one place. The BatteryClerk wholesale program should be considered.</p>
<p><strong>Who Needs Wholesale Batteries</strong></p>
<p>Perhaps you are a school administrator who has just been informed that all of the laptops in the district require <span><a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections">replacement batteries</a></span>. Maybe you run a chain of stores with motorized shopping carts that run on rechargeable batteries. Whatever your battery requirements, you need the correct battery that will give you the peace of mind that you have backups on hand, ready to keep your equipment powered up. Don’t forget, they also need to be good quality and not break the budget.</p>
<p>BatteryClerk welcomes</p>
<ul>
<li>Wholesalers and distributors</li>
<li>Retailers and resellers</li>
<li>OEMs</li>
<li>schools and hospitals</li>
<li>municipalities and other government agencies</li>
<li>warehouses and commercial organizations</li>
<li>any high volume battery users</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Quality Batteries and Excellent Customer Service</strong></p>
<p>At BatteryClerk, we pride ourselves on providing great customer service and high quality batteries, whether you are buying one battery, or a pallet of batteries. Some of the benefits of purchasing through our Wholesaler Program are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Free shipping</li>
<li>30 day money back guarantee</li>
<li>Volume discounts</li>
<li>Credit available for qualified buyers</li>
<li>Purchase orders, government and school credit cards accepted</li>
<li>
<span> </span>Our own brand, <span><a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/ajc-sealed-lead-acid-batteries">AJC® sealed lead acid batteries</a></span>
</li>
<li>Custom discounts for customers with a <span>wholesale battery account</span>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Plan Ahead</strong></p>
<p>Planning for volume battery replacement and for keeping batteries on hand for peak usage periods just got a lot easier. We also have a huge selection of batteries, making BatteryClerk a great one stop shop for your replacement battery needs. Our battery experts will be able to steer you to the right batteries for your application.</p>
<p>So whether you are reselling our quality batteries, using them to power equipment for your business, or keeping them on hand to keep your township laptops in working order, <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/pages/wholesale-batteries" title="Wholesale batteries">apply for a wholesale battery account</a> and get a custom quote on the quality replacement batteries you need for a competitive price.</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IyyFy5aCdwI" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/lithium-ion-replacement-battery-benefits-and-maintenance-tips</id>
    <published>2020-07-14T11:44:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-07-14T11:44:50-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/lithium-ion-replacement-battery-benefits-and-maintenance-tips"/>
    <title>Lithium Ion Replacement Battery Benefits and Maintenance Tips</title>
    <author>
      <name>Aric Shelko</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span style="color: #000000; font-family: 'Helvetica Neue', Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 15px; font-style: normal; font-variant-ligatures: normal; font-variant-caps: normal; font-weight: 400; letter-spacing: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; text-decoration-style: initial; text-decoration-color: initial; display: inline !important; float: none;">Lithium Ion (also known as Li-ion) has risen in popularity over recent years with more dependence on our electronic devices from laptops and cell phones to barcodes scanners and multimeters. We look at the benefits and offer up some tips on best practice for maintaining your Li-ion batteries.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/lithium-ion-replacement-battery-benefits-and-maintenance-tips">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Lithium Ion (also known as Li-ion) has risen in popularity over recent years especially as we continue to be more and more dependent on our electronic devices from <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/laptop-and-notebook-batteries" title="Laptop replacement batteries">laptops</a> and cell phones to <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/barcode-batteries" title="Barcode scanner replacement batteries">barcodes scanners</a> and multimeters. One key element with li-ion batteries is the need for them to be small and light and low maintenance and these guys certainly fit the bill. So let’s have a look at some of the key features of li-ion batteries.</p>
<p><b>Maintenance</b> – as stated above, these guys are pretty low maintenance. There’s no need to top up with acid or water, there’s no need to fully discharge periodically and typically does not need to be removed from its device. It really does not require any significant maintenance.</p>
<p><b>Performance</b> – most devices that run on li-ion batteries, need it to last for a decent amount of time before requiring recharging. Cell phones in particular typically need to last all day but that battery needs to be powerful enough to keep it going. It’s a delicate balance but one the li-ion is very capable of doing given its high energy density.</p>
<p><b>Discharge</b> – most rechargeable batteries have something known as self-discharge which is essentially a chemical reaction inside the batteries and reduces the overall effectiveness of a battery over time. Li-ion self-discharges at a much lower rate than say a NiMH or NiCd.</p>
<p><b>Environment</b> – Li-ion batteries are often used in electric vehicles which significantly reduces carbon emission, but they can also be recycled. It is important to note that they need to be handled and broken down safely so not all recycling centers can handle them. Find a location that will accept them and dispose of appropriately.</p>
<p>While Li-ion batteries are low maintenance, there are a few things that will help extend their lifespan.</p>
<ol>
<li>Temperature – these batteries love a temperate climate particularly around 68F to 77F or room temperature so extremes on either side can impact its overall lifespan.</li>
<li>Partial Discharge – The recommendation from most manufacturers is to use only 25% of the battery capacity before recharging.</li>
<li>Full Discharge – while it’s good to regularly do the partial discharge, they suggest hitting a full discharge every 20 or 30 times.</li>
<li>Full Capacity – Keeping the battery constantly at full capacity will shorten battery life so make sure to unplug regularly.</li>
<li>Battery Chargers – typically using the manufacturers charger is recommended but people will often grab a spare or a cheap knockoff causing current fluctuations which will damage the battery.</li>
<li>Storage – if you’re planning on storing the battery for an extended period of time, discharge to about 50% before storing in a dry, cool environment. Some suggest the refrigerator but if possible, a basement is best.</li>
</ol>
<p>BatteryClerk carries a large range of <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections" title="Lithium Ion replacement batteries">replacement Lithium Ion batteries</a> for a wide range of products. Head to our website and search for your product to see if we’ve got what you need.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/barcode-scanner-replacement-batteries</id>
    <published>2020-07-06T15:54:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-07-06T17:00:50-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/barcode-scanner-replacement-batteries"/>
    <title>Barcode Scanner Replacement Batteries</title>
    <author>
      <name>Aric Shelko</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Most barcode scanners run on rechargeable batteries. Learn how to replace the batteries in your scanner with BatteryClerk's quality replacement batteries to keep your scanner operating at peak efficiency.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/barcode-scanner-replacement-batteries">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/barcode-batteries" title="Barcode Scanners">barcode scanner</a> was invented to meet the need to accurately and quickly check out of the grocery store. Drexel Institute University turned down the project, but a couple of enterprising students who overheard the conversation took up the challenge, and were issued a patent in 1952.</p>
<p>Barcode scanners are a ubiquitous part of our lives.  Stop into a large box store and you can scan your own items, pay for them and generate the receipt with a hand held scanner.  Most people don’t remember cashiers keying each price into the register at the local grocery store. In our fast paced world, this is a good thing!</p>
<p>At the hospital, your plastic id bracelet is scanned by nurses at every step of the treatment process. The data encoded on that bracelet needs to be accessible and error-free every step of the way.</p>
<p>Warehouses depend on scanners for inventory control, and production lines use them to keep the manufacturing process smooth and efficient.</p>
<p><strong>Rechargeable Barcode Scanner Batteries</strong></p>
<p>Wireless scanners use rechargeable batteries. The batteries can last for thousands of scans, depending on the scanner model and the age of the battery. The battery will recharge in a few hours, again varying on the type and age of the battery that powers the scanner.</p>
<p>The batteries often can be charged up to 300 times before they need to be replaced. If you use the device every day, you will probably need to replace the batteries once a year although some batteries will last longer. Because scanners are an integral part of what you do, you will want a quality, <span><a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/ajc-sealed-lead-acid-batteries" title="AJC Replacement Batteries">reliable replacement battery</a></span> on hand.</p>
<p><strong>Replacing the Batteries in a Barcode Scanner</strong></p>
<p>Although barcode scanners differ in style and intended use, replacing the battery is similar for each. </p>
<ol>
<li>Locate the door to the battery compartment and remove it, taking note of any details that will help you replace it. Some doors just pop or slide off, some are held in place with a screw that will need to be removed, usually with a Philips head screw driver.</li>
<li>Take note of how the battery is oriented in the compartment.</li>
<li>If there are wires, disconnect them at the connection point, if not pop the battery out.</li>
<li>Reconnect the new battery wires and place the battery back into the compartment, or snap the new battery in place.</li>
<li>Replace the battery compartment door.</li>
<li>The unit may need to be re-paired with the base before it works. Place the scanner in its cradle for a few seconds and it will be ready to scan.</li>
</ol>
<p><span>BatteryClerk</span> offers high-quality, <span><a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/barcode-batteries">barcode replacement batteries</a></span> that are compatible with many of the OEM (original equipment manufacturer) batteries of major brands of scanners.  They will give you the superior performance and the optimum power you need. When you factor in the excellent customer service and free shipping, the value of OEM replacement batteries from BatteryClerk becomes even more evident. Whether your barcode scanner is in a retail, medical or manufacturing setting, having reliable OEM replacement batteries on hand will make sure your scanners are always working at peak efficiency.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/replacing-your-alarm-system-battery</id>
    <published>2020-06-15T13:13:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-06-15T23:22:21-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/replacing-your-alarm-system-battery"/>
    <title>Replacing your Alarm System Battery</title>
    <author>
      <name>Aric Shelko</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<span style="color: #000000; font-family: 'Helvetica Neue', Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 15px; font-style: normal; font-variant-ligatures: normal; font-variant-caps: normal; font-weight: 400; letter-spacing: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; text-decoration-style: initial; text-decoration-color: initial; display: inline !important; float: none;">Protecting your home with an alarm system is important for many. Ensuring that the system is fully operational is a critical part of that and often the battery or backup battery is a point of failure. We show you how to find a replacement alarm battery and also step to replace your alarm system battery.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/replacing-your-alarm-system-battery">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>You’re doing the right thing by protecting your prized possessions including your loved ones with an alarm system. Having proven to have prevented many burglaries and home invasions through the years, that extra peace of mind you get by having a security system is worth its weight.</p>
<p>Some alarm systems are hard-wired to the house with a <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/alarm-batteries" title="Alarm Battery category">backup alarm battery</a> in case the power goes out (or is cut) while others run strictly off battery power. Alarm companies generally do a great job setting up and responding in case there is an incident but something out of their typical wheelhouse is ongoing maintenance. We’ve heard of alarms going off spontaneously or sometimes not even working due to a bad battery, a drained battery or an old backup battery. False alarms can be more than a nuisance but a non-working battery can be downright dangerous.</p>
<h3>What can you do to ensure better alarm battery system performance?</h3>
<p>Replace the battery regularly or have a backup on standby.</p>
<h3>Should You Do it Yourself or go through the Alarm Company?</h3>
<p>Depending on your alarm company, asking them to come out and check or replace your batteries can incur a fee. Not only could the visit cost you but the battery itself can cost upward of $120 for a battery we sell for $15.</p>
<h3>How Often Should You Replace your Alarm System Battery?</h3>
<p>To be on the safe side, we suggest updating every 3 to 5 years. Even though battery technology continues to evolve, given the importance of having a working alarm system the cost is minimal and the risk vs. cost isn’t worth it.</p>
<h3>How Do You Know What Battery to Get?</h3>
<p>Your current alarm battery most likely has a model number plus some additional information that could be useful. Check on the battery for a number. Our example shows a CA1240</p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0005/3175/9163/files/BC1_large.jpg?v=1547833045" alt="Battery model number CA1240"></p>
<p>It also includes some additional information which may be useful: 12V (you’ll want to match this, it represents the number of volts). 4AH means 4 amperes which is the total amount of charge a battery can deliver in an hour. General rule here is that there is minimal difference between 4Ah and 5Ah but the size and dimensions will remain the same so it will easily fit in the casing.</p>
<p>So to look for our battery that matches, we head to <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca" title="BatteryClerk.ca website">batteryclerk.ca</a> and do a search for “CA1240”. The top results also match the brand of our old one:</p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0005/3175/9163/files/BC5_medium.jpg?v=1547833200" alt="BatteryClerk search"></p>
<p>At $13.29 you’re looking at a quarter of the price from most alarm companies and half that of the manufacturer.</p>
<h3><strong><span>How Do You Switch the Batteries?</span></strong></h3>
<p>Obviously the method for switching batteries varies from service to service but generally it’s pretty straightforward.</p>
<ol>
<li>Most alarm systems will have a test mode or similar which will prevent any false alarms. You can typically do this through the control panel.</li>
<li>Locate your system panel (often in the basement or closet)<br><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0005/3175/9163/files/BC2_large.jpg?v=1547833574" alt="alarm system control panel">
</li>
<li>Open up the panel door and locate the current battery. Make a note of where the current cables are attached to the terminals.</li>
<li>Switch the cables from the current battery to the new battery and place carefully back in the system panel.</li>
</ol>
<br><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0005/3175/9163/files/BC3_large.jpg?v=1547833671" alt="Alarm battery wiring"><br><br><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0005/3175/9163/files/BC4_large.jpg?v=1547833762" alt="alarm battery connection"><br><br>
<p>Now you can turn off test mode and that’s pretty much all that needs to be done to ensure your peace of mind and to maintain the security of your home.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/benefits-of-battery-powered-lawn-mower-and-garden-equipment</id>
    <published>2020-06-08T23:32:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-06-09T11:38:19-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/benefits-of-battery-powered-lawn-mower-and-garden-equipment"/>
    <title>Top 5 Advantages of Battery Powered Lawn Mower and Garden Equipment</title>
    <author>
      <name>Aric Shelko</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span style="color: #000000; font-family: 'Helvetica Neue', Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 15px; font-style: normal; font-variant-ligatures: normal; font-variant-caps: normal; font-weight: 400; letter-spacing: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; text-decoration-style: initial; text-decoration-color: initial; display: inline !important; float: none;">Lawn and garden equipment has come quite a way since gas and push powered were the only options. We break down our top 5 advantages of going battery.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/benefits-of-battery-powered-lawn-mower-and-garden-equipment">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Lawn and garden equipment has come quite a way since gas and push-powered were the only options. While gas powered equipment has evolved somewhat, battery powered options have really come along in leaps and bounds. From lawn mowers to trimmers, tillers, weed whackers, and chain saws, there are many more battery powered options to choose from. While range and runtime is probably the main differentiator between choosing gas over battery, there are many other reasons for choosing battery over gas. As yards and properties become smaller, most battery powered equipment should be able to cover tasks that are within a 60 minute timeframe.</p>
<p>Battery-powered lawn equipment has significantly increased in popularity so what’s the appeal of battery over gas?</p>
<p><strong>Cost</strong> – generally battery powered equipment like lawn mowers can cost a little more than their gas counterparts initially but gas costs and maintenance costs will continue but batteries only have to be replaced every few years. Over time you’ll most likely see savings on electric options.</p>
<p><strong>Maintenance</strong> – gas powered equipment requires regular servicing, oil changes/fills, fuel filters, spark plugs. Oil changes can be pretty messy and time consuming if you choose to do it yourself or expensive if you need to take it somewhere to get maintained. Maintenance on battery-powered equipment is minimal.</p>
<p><strong>Operating</strong> – many of us who have had gas powered mowers before have probably experienced the pull cord dramas that comes with it. Sweating it out on a hot summer day when your mower or weed whacker won’t start is not fun. Conversely, battery powered devices start with the turn of a key and the push of a button.</p>
<p><strong>Environment</strong>– zero emissions is certainly appealing but gas powered equipment isn’t there yet, not even close. It’s true that batteries need to be charged by electricity, which is often coal powered but the amounts are still nominal in comparison.</p>
<p><strong>Noise</strong> – not necessarily a game-changer but something that may be relevant in situations where noise sensitivity is important. Battery powered equipment is considerably quieter than their gas powered counterparts.</p>
<p>Naturally, you need to choose the option that is right for you but the appeal of battery powered lawn and garden equipment should be quite obvious especially for those of us who live in a suburban setting. As houses get bigger and yards get smaller, we want something cleaner and more manageable. BatteryClerk.ca has a whole category of replacement batteries dedicated to <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/lawn-and-garden-batteries">lawn and garden equipment</a> for most top brands available throughout Canada.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/is-my-electric-scooter-battery-dead</id>
    <published>2020-06-01T10:33:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-06-02T22:28:04-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/is-my-electric-scooter-battery-dead"/>
    <title>Is My Electric Scooter Battery Dead?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Aric Shelko</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[You've dusted off the electric scooter as the weather warms up but it doesn't want to start. Your first suspect should probably be the battery so here are a few things you might want to look at when finding a suitable replacement battery.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/is-my-electric-scooter-battery-dead">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>The weather is finally getting nicer and you're clamoring to ride your electric scooter, but it won't start! The battery is a big factor for making the scooter go, so let's start there.</p>
<p><strong>New Scooter </strong></p>
<p>If this is a new scooter, you need to fully charge the <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/electric-scooter-batteries" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">scooter battery</a> before riding it for the first time. Most batteries are delivered with some charge, but don't be tempted. Fully charge it first!</p>
<p>After you ride it, charge it again. Every time.</p>
<p>Make sure you switch the scooter's power button to the off position when you are not riding. That way you can preserve battery life by not wasting battery power.</p>
<p><strong>Storing the Scooter</strong></p>
<p>If you are storing the <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/electric-scooter-batteries/brand_razor">Razor scooter</a> for a few wintry months, charge it every 30 days. A battery that gets too low may not recharge. However, don't leave it plugged into the charger for more than 24 hours. Charge it for the minimal amount of time suggested by the manufacturer, typically 6 to 8 hours, or until the battery charge light turns green.</p>
<p>Don't store the battery in a space that gets below 50 degrees Fahrenheit (10 degrees Celsius). Absolutely don't let it freeze!</p>
<p><strong>When the Battery is Low</strong></p>
<p>If the scooter is slow or sluggish, the horn sounds wimpy and the lights are dimming, the battery probably needs to be charged. Your user manual will tell you about how far or how long your scooter should perform on a full charge, but the power will usually diminish towards the end of that cycle. The power will also diminish when the battery is reaching the end of its useful life. It will only charge for a set number of cycles and after that will need to be replaced.</p>
<p>Make sure you have the charger that came with your scooter or that you have purchased a good quality charger. Lesser quality chargers may take a long time to charge your battery or may never fully charge it. There can also be connection issues with lower quality chargers.</p>
<p>These batteries don't have a 'memory' and don't need to be fully discharged prior to recharging. As a matter of fact, completely discharging the battery is NOT recommended, as it may prevent it from holding a charge in the future. When a lead-acid battery is not charged, it gets a buildup of sulfate-ion inside. This buildup will prematurely age your battery and is the reason batteries no longer accept a full charge.</p>
<p><strong>A Spare </strong></p>
<p>Consider purchasing a <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/electric-scooter-batteries" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">spare electric scooter </a>battery. That way you can continue to ride while one battery is charging and swap them out as needed. You won't be sidelined by a dead or dying battery!</p>
<p>If you maintain your Razor scooter battery properly from the beginning, it will provide you with 3 or 4 years of fun!</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/can-sealed-lead-acid-batteries-be-recycled</id>
    <published>2020-05-26T14:08:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-05-26T14:08:32-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/can-sealed-lead-acid-batteries-be-recycled"/>
    <title>Can Sealed Lead Acid Batteries be Recycled?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Aric Shelko</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Many people may be surprised to learn that nearly 95% of SLA battery components can be recycled making it one of the most recyclable products around. We offer up some recommendations for what you can do with your old battery to ensure it gets appropriately reused.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/can-sealed-lead-acid-batteries-be-recycled">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[SLA Batteries are an important part of our lives but they do have a limited lifespan so what do you do when they’ve come to the end of their run? Chances are these items are banned from landfills and rightly so. Incinerators are out of the question due to their toxic nature. So what do you do with them?<br><br> Interestingly, many of its components are actually recyclable. The plastic that most of them are made out of can be recycled plus the lead which can be reused in new batteries so by many estimates, about 85% - 95% of all SLA batteries can be reused in some fashion. We’re all very familiar with the benefits of recycling (cleaner planet, natural mineral conservation, minimize energy etc) so the fact that most components in our batteries are able to be recycled is good news indeed.<br><br> The process itself is quite interesting. Essentially the batteries are crushed and then go into a water separating process to pull the lead and plastic away from each other. The lead sinks to the bottom, the plastic to the top. Here’s a good video explanation going over the actual recycling process.<br><br> <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fnuCCpab4KQ" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0"></iframe>
<h3>What to do with your old SLA battery?</h3>
<p>With that in mind, it’s important to know how you can actually go about recycling your battery. At BatteryClerk we accept Lead Acid Batteries (SLA, VRLA, AGM) for our recycling program, you’ll just need to ship it to our head office in New Jersey. The battery casings are very durable so shipping is no problem, and many will often ship a whole pallet to the BatteryClerk headquarters where they are then sent to the appropriate recycling center.</p>
<p>There may also be drop off locations around you where you can take them to be responsibly disposed. A lot of car part and auto shops will certainly take car batteries and many of them will take other kinds.</p>
<p>It might also be worth investigating specific waste and recycling centers in your city or town. Many have free locations where you can drop off batteries rather than having to ship or dump them (which you should never do).</p>
<p>There are also some interesting services cropping up that are specifically designed to recycle batteries. Call2Recycle offers several locations around the US and Canada for a variety of battery types as well as packaging solutions where you can safety pack and ship your battery.</p>
<p>All of the BatteryClerk global websites has details on where to send your batteries. In the US it’s <a href="https://batteryclerk.com/pages/battery-recycling">New Jersey</a>, Canada is in <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/pages/battery-recycling">Ottawa</a> and most of the EU locations can be sent to <a href="https://batteryclerk.nl/pages/battery-recycling">The Netherlands</a>. Check our pages for more details.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/generator-replacement-battery-planning-and-maintenance</id>
    <published>2020-04-20T16:41:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-04-22T11:48:27-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/generator-replacement-battery-planning-and-maintenance"/>
    <title>Generator Replacement Battery Planning and Maintenance</title>
    <author>
      <name>Accounting BatteryClerk</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[With the increasing number of hurricanes, typhoons and other natural disasters that result in power outages for hours or longer, it is important to make sure your generator is ready for the day you might need to use it.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/generator-replacement-battery-planning-and-maintenance">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Backup generators are often purchased in anticipation of a weather event, or as a result of an outage caused by a weather event. They are often stored and forgotten until the weather forecast predicts another storm with enough intensity that power could be disrupted. However, your generator could be useless if the battery has not been properly maintained.</p>
<p>Even a generator that is powered by gasoline, natural gas or propane needs a battery to start and to run any electronic components. Generators typically use <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/sealed-lead-acid-batteries" title="Sealed Lead Acid Batteries"><span>sealed lead acid batteries</span>,</a> and, like all types of batteries, they will lose charge, or self-discharge, when not being used. Once a sealed lead acid battery has been allowed to discharge too much, it won’t take or hold a charge and will need to be replaced.</p>
<p><strong>Generator Battery Maintenance</strong></p>
<p>Like most automobile batteries, <span><a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/generator-batteries" title="Generator Batteries">generator batteries</a></span> don’t require a lot of attention. But unlike most cars, a generator may not be used enough for its batteries to remain charged. To make sure your battery is ready for the next storm, measure the charge with a digital voltmeter or a multimeter. If it falls below 12.4 volts, it needs to be re-charged.</p>
<p>One way to make sure the battery stays charged and ready is with a trickle charger. This charger stays connected to the battery and monitors the charge, initiating a charging cycle based on the volts. All you need to do is to periodically check the battery and charger to make sure the connections are tight and there is no corrosion or dirt accumulating on terminals or wiring.</p>
<p><strong>Replace the Batteries</strong></p>
<p>With good maintenance, your generator battery will still need to be replaced every 2 or 3 years. If you don’t maintain it regularly or if it is stored in a space that is too cold or too hot, plan on replacing it more often. The last thing you want when the power is out is for your battery to not be strong enough to start your generator.</p>
<p>BatteryClerk offers high-quality, AJC-brand generator replacement batteries that are built to last.  They give you the superior performance and the optimum power you need. When you use <span><a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/ajc-sealed-lead-acid-batteries" title="AJC Replacement Batteries">AJC replacement batteries</a></span>, you have peace of mind that you will have the power you need when the grid is down.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/how-to-find-a-replacement-battery</id>
    <published>2020-02-11T11:18:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-02-11T11:18:18-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/how-to-find-a-replacement-battery"/>
    <title>How to Find a Replacement Battery</title>
    <author>
      <name>Aric Shelko</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[There are typically several ways to identify a replacement for your battery and not all of them have to take a lot of time nor break the bank. We offer several tips for locating your replacement battery on batteryclerk.ca.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/how-to-find-a-replacement-battery">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Your equipment probably came with a battery already installed but eventually that battery is going to stop working. Batteries typically have a shelf life between 3-5 years depending on the type of battery, its maintenance and of course how hard it needs to work.</p>
<p>There are typically several ways to identify a replacement for your battery and not all of them have to take a lot of time nor break the bank.<br><br>1. <strong>Model Numbers</strong> – most batteries will have a model number as identification. Sometimes it’s located on a sticker which if worn out, makes it tough to ID, but those that do can be used to search for your exact replacement. If the current one is a Yuasa YTX12-BS simply search in BatteryClerk.com and the first result will typically be the best option for you. In this case you’ll find it <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/products/yuasa-ytx12-bs-replacement-battery">here</a>.</p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0011/2964/4068/files/partners-ms_large.png?v=1573537521" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><br>2. <strong>Part Numbers</strong> – again these may be on a sticker or often stamped into the casing. If both options are scuffed it can be tricky but more often that not, if the battery is in a protected area, it should be highly visible. If your Mobility scooter shows a part number of SLADC12-35j, again put that in our search to find your <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/products/duracell-sladc12-35j-sladc12-35j-12v-7ah-sealed-lead-acid-replacement-battery">compatible replacement battery</a>.</p>
<p><br>3. <strong>Combinations</strong> – sometimes you might be able to find what you need by searching for some features that you know.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><strong>Amps and Voltage</strong> – this one can be tricky as there can be several battery types with the same Ah and V but if you combine these with other known features, you may be able to drill down to find your match.<br><strong>Battery Type</strong> – if the battery is for a UPS device, emergency light or other, you can use that information to find several options. <br><strong>Dimension</strong> – making sure your battery fits in the available compartment can be a cause of frustration so leveraging this to find your replacement can be useful.<br><strong>Equipment Brand</strong> – there are a lot out there but we’ve included as many as possible on batteryclerk.com so this can be a useful way to find your replacement.</p>
<p>When you combine several of these features, the chances of finding your exact replacement should increase. If you search for Type (wheelchair for example) dimension (something like 7.8 x 5.2 x 6.4) and even brand (Golden Technologies), you can often find your <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/products/golden-technologies-liteway-12v-22ah-wheelchair-replacement-battery">compatible replacement unit</a>. This method is a little more of an inexact science so try some different combinations first (Ah, V + brand) or (Ah, V + Dimensions).<br><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0011/2964/4068/files/wheelchair_large_8caba1f4-8463-4abd-9de7-a3da257a8f68_grande.jpg?v=1580827207" alt="wheelchair battery replacement search"></p>
<p><br>At BatteryClerk we can get the batteries out within 1-2 days for shipping to most of the U.K. so you can have your replacement battery in place and ready to go. Just remove the cables from the old battery, take the old battery out of its compartment, put the new one in the same place as the old and re-attach the same cables. Some batteries will require clamps or other methods to keep them in place more securely. Check out our <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/pages/infographics" title="Replacement battery infographics">infographics</a> for more details.</p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0011/2964/4068/files/BC-search_large_36c72898-136e-467b-9140-aba61f620819_large.jpg?v=1580827318" alt=""></p>
<p><br>The BatteryClerk.com search function has been designed to make searching for your replacement battery easier. Obviously, the more information you can glean from your current battery, the more accurate you can be. Also keep in mind that not all batteries are created the same. We manufacture AJC batteries for top performance and to withstand extreme conditions which in turn helps to reduce returns, customer satisfaction and all-round good experiences.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/ride-on-toy-battery-replacement</id>
    <published>2020-01-02T11:09:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-01-02T11:09:33-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/ride-on-toy-battery-replacement"/>
    <title>Ride on Toy Battery Replacement</title>
    <author>
      <name>Aric Shelko</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Keeping your child’s battery operated car in tip top shape means taking care of that battery or getting the right replacement battery!</p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/ride-on-toy-battery-replacement">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Your child is the proud owner of a ride on toy car and absolutely loves tooling around the neighborhood showing it off. But just like your car won't go far if you forget to stop at the filling station, your child will be grounded if the battery is dead or won't hold a charge.</p>
<p><strong>Increasing Performance</strong></p>
<p>Batteries that come with ride on toys are typically just powerful enough to run the vehicle. However, when you need to replace the battery, or if you want a spare to keep the 4 wheel fun moving, you can purchase a <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/search_results?type=product&amp;k=ride+on+toy+replacement+batteries&amp;grid_list=list-view">replacement ride on toy battery</a> with the same voltage but with higher amp hours. Typically you can find the higher amp replacement battery that will still fit correctly in the battery compartment. Higher amps will allow the toy to run longer on one charge. It is a lot like a gas tank in your family car. The bigger the tank the longer between fill ups. Well, the more amps, the longer between charging sessions.</p>
<p><strong>Chargers</strong></p>
<p>You are going to want to invest in a decent quality battery charger for the type of battery that runs your child's wheels. The chargers that come with the toy usually needs to be unplugged after a specified time limit or the battery will overcharge, limiting its useful life. A smart charger delivers a low amperage charge, and features circuitry that senses when your battery is fully charged. It then stops charging and monitors the voltage. If it senses a drop in voltage, the smart charger will re-activate and top off the charge without harming the battery.</p>
<p><strong>Replacement Battery Check</strong></p>
<p>If the car only runs for a short time, there are other things to check besides the battery. Is the load on the car too heavy? Check the recommended weight from the manufacturer. If the car is being ridden on grass or up a slope, there will be more power required from the battery, and it will not run as long as on a flat sidewalk. Also, check the optimal temperature for riding the car. If it's too hot or too cold, the battery may not provide the same mileage.</p>
<p>In the off season, don't store the ride on toy battery when it is not fully charged. These batteries work best and last longest when their charge is maintained. Also don't store it where the temperature fluctuates from hot to cold and back, as that also shortens the battery life.</p>
<p>Battery life for these toys can be 2 or 3 years if the battery is properly maintained. But keep in mind that as the battery ages, it will begin to lose capacity, meaning it won't go quite as far on a full charge as it did when the battery was new so make sure your kid keeps those road trips close to home.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/what-is-a-factory-activated-battery</id>
    <published>2019-12-02T21:49:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2019-12-02T21:49:34-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/what-is-a-factory-activated-battery"/>
    <title>What is a Factory Activated Battery?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Aric Shelko</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span>If you’re shopping for a replacement battery, you may have come across the term “factory activated” which has left you scratching your head. So what does it actually mean?</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/what-is-a-factory-activated-battery">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[If you’re shopping for a replacement battery, you may have come across mention of “factory activated” which has left you scratching your head. So what does it actually mean when it’s factory activated and does it have advantages or disadvantages over the “non” factory activated options?<br><br> When it says factory activated, the first thing of note is that it typically means that the battery is AGM (absorbed glass mat), which is a popular battery variation that gained its popularity in the 1980’s. Around that time they saw significant technical improvements particularly the benefit of being spill proof, allowing the battery to be placed in any position, which is applicable for a lot of vehicles. It also meant that they could make them a lot lighter. The AGM’s decreased weight also made it attractive for vehicles and equipment where weight is important.<br><meta charset="utf-8"><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0005/3175/9163/files/cutaway_large.jpg?v=1560544077" alt="" width="388" height="380"><br> Additionally, many vehicles need something durable enough to tackle rugged terrains and not break or spill easily, most have high-impact polypropylene casing for maximum vibration resistance. AGM batteries are perfect as they are light and durable.<br><br> Still, not all AGM batteries are created equal. Some AGM batteries will need to be filled and charged on arrival. These are not factory activated. These will come with an acid pack that gets added to the holes at the top of the battery prior to sealing and then requires charging. Other types of AGM batteries do not require filling or charging as they have already been filled and charged prior to shipping or “factory activated” and will be ready to go upon arrival. <br><br> The setup and activation process for non factory activated batteries these days is certainly a lot easier than it used to be but the filling and charging process is not without its issues. The acid packages often come in handy contained packages that are separated by cells and as a result, far less likely to spill so they’re a lot safer but there are still some risks so you’re going to have to take safety precautions during the sulfuric acid filling process as it can be fairly damaging to skin, you definitely don’t want to get it in your eyes. Once filled, you’re then going to have to start the charging process. Charging time depends on your charger and the type of battery you use but some will require up to 8 hours to fully charge. Factory activated avoids the need for filling and charging.<br><br> When you see “maintenance free factory activated”, you know that your battery is ready to go as soon as it arrives and you are never going to have to go through the hassle of filling the acid or water as well as waiting for the battery to charge. <br><br> If you’re still curious about the battery activation process, check out <a href="https://youtu.be/jL9COQwseEg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">this video</a> which may be enough to deter you from going through the process yourself and seeking out factory activated batteries. If you’re looking for batteries that are ready to go, browse through the <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/">BatteryClerk website</a> to find your "factory activated" match.]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/tips-for-finding-a-replacement-battery-for-your-snowmobile</id>
    <published>2019-10-18T11:57:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2019-10-18T11:57:59-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/tips-for-finding-a-replacement-battery-for-your-snowmobile"/>
    <title>Tips for Finding a Replacement Battery for Your Snowmobile</title>
    <author>
      <name>Aric Shelko</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span>When it comes time to replace your current snowmobile battery which is no longer performing at its best, there are a few things to look for. We offer some tips when shopping around for a replacement snowmobile battery to make sure your vehicle starts every time.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/tips-for-finding-a-replacement-battery-for-your-snowmobile">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>When the snow starts coming down, the snowmobiles come out. In the northern states of the U.S, throughout Canada and Alaska and many countries in Northern Europe, people rely on their snowmobiles as their primary transport vehicle. For others, it may be for recreation or hunting purposes. Whatever the use, the snowmobile is a valuable asset for many. </p>
<p>The challenge with snowmobiles and many <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/ajc-powersports-batteries" title="Powersports Batteries">powersports</a> vehicles, is that they operate in extreme conditions. Temperatures often get extremely cold, often in rough terrain and at high altitudes all of which can impact a battery performance. Poor performance can ultimately lead to difficulty starting which, if in remote and extreme conditions, can be life threatening. </p>
<p>When it comes time to replace your current battery which is no longer performing at its best, here are a few things to look for. </p>
<ol>
<li>
<strong>CCA</strong> – all batteries have a measurement for rating performance in cold temperatures called Cold Cranking Amps (CCA). Essentially the higher the number, the greater its ability to start in the cold.</li>
<li>
<strong>Size and Layout</strong> – certainly one of the last things you want is for the battery to be getting tossed around so make sure it fits snugly in place. Some may also may be seated in a slight angle so having a battery that can handle that is critical (AGM for example)</li>
<li>
<strong>Compatibility</strong> – an incompatible battery will significantly impact a snowmobile’s performance and even in many instances, the snowmobile won’t start at all.</li>
</ol>
<p>These three options above should give you a good start in your replacement search. A few other things to note.</p>
<ul>
<li>Freshness is important so buying a battery straight out of the factory is going to perform better than one sitting on a shelf for months. A popular store like BatteryClerk who has a large turnover of batteries is your best bet.</li>
<li>Warranties are important so make sure there’s at least 30 days</li>
<li>Maintaining a charge through the offseason can help extend its left. A trickle charger is a worthwhile investment. </li>
</ul>
<p>Whether using your snowmobile for work or pleasure, making sure that it starts every time is crucial, and in some instances, essential. Having a <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/snowmobile-batteries" title="Replacement Snowmobile Battery">replacement snowmobile battery</a> that is reliable and can handle extreme conditions is a worthwhile investment and gives you one less thing to worry about when you’re braving the conditions.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/ajc-replacement-batteries-donated-to-gift-of-mobility-giveaway</id>
    <published>2019-09-17T21:24:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2019-09-17T21:25:46-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/ajc-replacement-batteries-donated-to-gift-of-mobility-giveaway"/>
    <title>AJC Replacement Batteries Donated to Gift Of Mobility Giveaway</title>
    <author>
      <name>Aric Shelko</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span>BatteryClerk learned of a program that provides refurbished mobility scooters to those who can’t afford them and as a result has donated a selection of mobility scooter replacement batteries to the program.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/ajc-replacement-batteries-donated-to-gift-of-mobility-giveaway">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>BatteryClerk learned of a program that provides refurbished mobility scooters to those who can’t afford them and as a result has donated a selection of mobility scooter replacement batteries to the program. With scooters ranging in price from $4,000 to $40,000, many with disabilities and mobility issues are simply unable to afford them and as a result struggle to move around freely.</p>
<p>BatteryClerk CEO Aric Shelko says “we heard about the program and could appreciate how beneficial it was to those in need. We take for granted the ability to get around easily but those with physical restrictions really rely on electric scooters and wheelchairs just to perform basic activities”</p>
<p>Mobility Scooters not only need to be mechanically sound but also need working batteries to provide power. The <a href="https://azpawngiftofmobility.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">AZ Pawn Gift of Mobility program</a> repairs broken scooters to make them functional again and BatteryClerk has donated replacement batteries to provide the power to get them running. Since 2009 the AZ Pawn Gift of Mobility Program has been refurbishing unwanted scooters and giving them away during the holiday season to those who cannot afford them. To date, they have given away over 600 scooters.</p>
<p>According to the program founder Phil Pavone “I am a cancer survivor who knows firsthand what these chairs mean to people. For those who are disabled these are much more than just a chair…. These are a means of independence, a chance to do normal things.”</p>
<p>BatteryClerk spotted the <a href="https://www.gofundme.com/giftofmobility%20" target="_blank" title="Gift of Mobility" rel="noopener noreferrer">GoFundMe page</a> at which talked about the need for scooter batteries. BatteryClerk has an extensive range of replacement batteries for most major brands of mobility scooters so it seemed to be a great fit. Shelko adds “it was a no-brainer for us. We saw an opportunity to contribute, so we have donated several compatible replacement batteries and look to continue that relationship.”</p>
<p>Those with unwanted scooters and wheelchairs around the Connecticut area are encouraged to send them to the program. Alternatively donations to the program can be made on their GoFundMe page.</p>
<p>BatteryClerk makes an effort to keep battery prices as low as possible to make it easier for mobility scooter users to find a replacement. Browse our <a href="https://batteryclerk.com/collections/scooter-batteries" title="mobility scooter replacement batteries">Mobility Scooter replacement batteries</a> to find your match.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/replacement-batteries-for-emergency-lights</id>
    <published>2019-08-28T22:41:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2019-08-28T22:41:35-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/replacement-batteries-for-emergency-lights"/>
    <title>Replacement Batteries for Emergency Lights</title>
    <author>
      <name>Aric Shelko</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<span>When the lights go out you need reliable backup power. To mitigate risk to people and property in the event that the electricity fails, your emergency lighting systems need to be ready at all times.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/replacement-batteries-for-emergency-lights">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>When the lights go out you need reliable backup power. In the event of a fire or other disaster that cuts off electricity, people and property can be at risk. To mitigate that risk, your emergency lighting systems need to be ready at all times.</p>
<p>Functional emergency lighting, or egress lighting, is often required to meet state building codes, fire codes, insurance standards and OSHA requirements. The emergency lighting must provide illumination for all egress routes automatically and within seconds in the event of a power failure. There are also guidelines for how and how often to test the emergency lighting system. A monthly test with the lights on for at least 30 seconds and a longer yearly test is common.</p>
<p><strong>How does emergency lighting work?</strong></p>
<p>Emergency lighting and exit signage lights work in a similar fashion. The lights are connect to the electrical system of the building providing a constant charge to the batteries. When the power goes out, the batteries kick in providing light to illuminate the hallways and stairs that are part of the emergency exit paths.</p>
<p><strong>When to replace the battery</strong></p>
<p>Most emergency lighting units have self-test switches that provide an accurate battery reading. When either the monthly test or the annual test generate unsatisfactory results, the battery needs to be replaced.</p>
<p>In optimal environments batteries can last longer than the typical 4 years indicated by manufacturers, but the results of the testing should dictate replacement whether or not they reach the 4 year mark.</p>
<iframe width="720" height="480" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZEoxrq4qBoI" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
<p><strong>Types of replacement batteries</strong></p>
<p>The <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/emergency-light-batteries" target="_blank" title="Emergency Light Battery" rel="noopener noreferrer">emergency lighting battery</a> must be replaced by a battery with the same voltage, dimensions and terminal type. For emergency lighting using sealed lead acid batteries, the voltage is usually 6v or 12v. Never replace a 12v battery with a 6v or a 6v with a 12v. This can cause your system to malfunction or cause damage to the lighting fixture.</p>
<p>The typical terminal type for a sealed lead acid backup battery is a faston tab. The fixture will be supplied with a connector that will slip over the tab on the battery to close the circuit. Some larger batteries have L terminals, which are also used on car batteries. These are rare unless the battery is large, and the fixture is rated for extended use during emergencies.</p>
<p>Although many exit signs now utilize LED bulbs and thus only require a small NiCad battery, there are older units and current dual units with emergency lights that are part of the exit sign that use <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/ajc-sealed-lead-acid-batteries" target="_blank" title="Sealed Lead Acid Batteries" rel="noopener noreferrer">sealed lead acid batteries.</a> Similar testing protocols are in place for these units and proper maintenance and periodic battery replacement should be considered just as essential. </p>
<p><strong>Where do I find alarm and emergency lighting replacement batteries?</strong></p>
<p>BatteryClerk.ca sells a wide variety of sealed lead acid batteries that are compatible with many brands of emergency lighting  and exit signs. They offer 1-2 day delivery to most of the USA plus FREE shipping on orders over $129.</p>
<p>BatteryClerk offers high-quality, <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/ajc-sealed-lead-acid-batteries" target="_blank" title="AJC Brand Sealed Lead Acid Batteries" rel="noopener noreferrer">AJC-brand batteries</a> that are built to last.  They give you the superior performance and the optimum power you need. When you use AJC replacement batteries, you have peace of mind that you will have the power, signage, and alerts needed in critical situations.</p>
<p><a href="https://BatteryClerk.ca" title="Shop BatteryClerk Canada">Shop BatteryClerk.ca</a> for your emergency lighting battery needs.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/ups-device-replacement-batteries</id>
    <published>2019-07-30T22:19:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2019-07-30T22:19:48-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/ups-device-replacement-batteries"/>
    <title>UPS Device Replacement Batteries</title>
    <author>
      <name>Aric Shelko</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[A UPS (Uninterruptible Power Supply) device allows your computers or servers to keep running for a short time when the primary power source is lost and also provides protection from power surges. Having a battery in good working order is critical as is having swift access to a reliable and affordable backup or replacement UPS battery.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/ups-device-replacement-batteries">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>A UPS (Uninterruptible Power Supply) device allows your computers or servers to keep running for a short time when the primary power source is lost and also provides protection from power surges which can happen often with Canada's extreme weather conditions. Given how critical your data and computer systems are, a UPS device is essential. Others also rely on UPS devices for their medical equipment at home where keeping things working is of great importance.</p>
<p>UPS devices contain a battery that activates when the device determines that power is lost, giving you time to save your work, investigate the or even potentially run an auxiliary power source like a generator (another reason why you should check the battery on your generator).</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/weJJQEB95Zw" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<p>You can understand then how valuable the role of the <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/ups-batteries" title="UPS Replacement Batteries">battery is for a UPS</a>, so it’s imperative that the battery is in full working order. After several years the battery will become less reliable so many encourage users to look to replace them between 3 and 5 years. Many UPS systems will send out an alert once the battery hits critical levels or will have some sort of signal (colored lights and an alarm) to let you know that there is an issue.</p>
<p>Two factors that can influence the life of the battery include:</p>
<ol>
<li>Environment – the temperature influences a battery performance and while the battery will certainly be able to operate under fairly extreme climates, its performance and lifespan will be impacted. As a general rule, look to store the battery at around 77 degrees.</li>
<li>Frequency – often referred to as cycling. When a battery is used and recharged often, it will influence the overall lifespan of your battery so make note of the number of times the battery is utilized.</li>
</ol>
<p>We also recommend measuring the battery regularly using a load tester which can be purchased online and will accurately tell you the battery condition. Doing so will ensure that even when your system goes down, your backup battery will reliably kick in and keep your systems going while you work on getting things back up and running. Here are some videos to help you test a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qKUpsqKKv9s">good</a> and a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R7yt_LtIP_0">bad</a> battery with a load tester.</p>
<p><span>BatteryClerk offers a lot of UPS replacement batteries for many of the leading brands at significantly lower prices, which can be a factor when purchasing a large amount, so browse our current <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/ups-batteries">UPS replacement battery</a> inventory.</span></p>
<p>View a UPS battery customer below </p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7CKadb3j3ew" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" frameborder="0"></iframe>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/replacing-powersports-batteries</id>
    <published>2019-06-28T16:48:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2019-06-28T16:48:14-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/replacing-powersports-batteries"/>
    <title>Replacing Powersports Batteries</title>
    <author>
      <name>Aric Shelko</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[Powersports equipment has grown quickly in popularity over the past 10 years around the world including Canada. Motorcycles are a great way to travel in urban and rural areas, ATV’s and UTV’s are a fun way to get dirty and explore or as a workhorse around farms. There are plenty of waterways throughout the country for Personal Watercraft vehicles but the country is incredibly well suited for snowmobiles, often as a primary mode of transportation during long winter months. <br><br> All these vehicles are equipped with a battery of some form. Given the role that many of these vehicles play, the vibrations, the bumps and the work they have to do, having a spill-proof battery is key. With that in mind, the valve regulated lead acid (VRLA) battery is the preferred choice and for us, the Absorbed Glass Mat is the best fit over gel which tends to lose power faster, especially at cooler temperatures.<br>
Some additional benefits of AGM batteries for powersports vehicles include:
<br>
<ol>
<li>Maintenance free – water is retained within the battery casing so no need to top up with distilled water.</li>
<li>Position – these batteries can be placed in virtually any position without loss of performance. Often this is necessary for some vehicles that have limited space.</li>
<li>Emissions – there is a reduced need for ventilation with these batteries and as such, they have little to no fumes.</li>
</ol>
But not all AGM batteries are created equal either. Some additional considerations that can influence performance include the amp hour (AH) will offer a measurement of how many amps a battery will draw. <br><br> Check the voltage. The voltage typically relates to the strength of a battery. Most powersports batteries are 12 volts.<br><br> CCA or cold cranking amps can also be a factor, particularly for snowmobiles which run in cold temperatures. <br><br> Also make sure to check on the size compatibility with your current setup. There may not be a perfect fit for some replacements so adding a little padding around the sides may be necessary, but try to get as close as possible especially with the amount of movement they have to accommodate. The last thing you want is your battery bouncing around.<br><br> Now available on <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca" title="BatterClerk Canada">BatteryClerk Canada</a>, our Powersports replacement batteries are compatible with most major brands of Motorcycles, ATV’s, UTV’s, Snowmobiles and Personal Watercraft. <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/powersports-batteries" title="Powersports Battery Collection">Browse our selection today</a>.]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/what-is-a-battery-backup-sump-pump-system</id>
    <published>2019-05-21T13:22:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2019-05-21T22:20:13-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/what-is-a-battery-backup-sump-pump-system"/>
    <title>What is a Battery Backup Sump Pump System?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Aric Shelko</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Sump Pumps can be a very necessary addition to a house or building. But what happens when your sump pump has issues and won't work during a storm? That's where a backup battery-powered sump pump kicks in and saves the day. We explain how it works.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/what-is-a-battery-backup-sump-pump-system">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>For those home and building owners who need a sump pump, you know how important it is to keep water away from areas it doesn’t belong. But what happens if the power goes out and your sump pump can’t operate? A sump pump is often only used during times when the weather is at its most active. Some may be required during light rain, activating for a few minutes every hour but other times it is utilized when the rains are a bit more active. Often with the more extreme weather comes issues like blackouts, downed tree limbs or power surges. Other times human error is a factor, like forgetting to plug it back in or not cleaning it regularly to make sure the float switch doesn’t get caught on debris. If your sump pump is over 5 years old, it may be a little less reliable so having a backup can really save you headaches especially if your house is prone to flooding.</p>
<p>One of the more popular types of sump pump backups is battery powered. Often, sump pump backup battery systems are added during the installation but that’s not always the case so sometimes you’ll have to add a separate backup pump. You can also replace the main pump or both with a combination sump pump and backup battery system, which is often a great option.</p>
<p><strong>What are the Backup Battery options for Sump Pumps?</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>
<em>Inverter / Battery add-on</em> – this method relies on the current sump pump but simply replaces the power source with battery power via the inverter. If the main power goes out, it automatically switches to the backup battery to power the primary sump pump. </li>
</ol>
<ol start="2">
<li>
<em>Auxiliary sump pump</em> – this is a separate unit that takes over when the primary unit is off or unable to keep up with the flow. Typically it will be smaller than the primary unit but still often requires modifying the area during installation. Some auxiliary sump pumps simply sit over the top of your current sump pump, making installation a bit easier.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="3">
<li>
<em>Combo Primary and Auxiliary Sump Pumps</em> – these are often best when you’re doing an initial install or completely need to replace your old sump pump. These ones are the dream team of sump pumps, tying together your main unit with a backup pump all under the one unit.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>How Long will a Backup Sump Pump Battery Run For?</strong></p>
<p>When the power goes out and the battery kicks in, hopefully you have enough power to run the pump during the outage. If your pump only kicks in once a day, you could easily run for a month but one that has to operate every minute is looking more like 1 day operations which should be enough during an outage but certainly sometimes during catastrophic incidents, you might be out of luck!</p>
<p><strong>How Often Should a Sump Pump Battery be Replaced?</strong></p>
<p>Sump Pumps average life expectancy tends to be around 10 years, somewhat dependent on how aggressively it has to operate as well as sizing, quality, installation. The backup battery for the pumps generally last between 3-5 years, even if they’re not heavily used.</p>
<p>Most options for sump pumps will include an alarm or warning systems, some include Wifi connectivity to provide status reports and some will offer phone alerts but the main factor you need to consider for a sump pump and a backup is how powerful it is. Will both the primary and backup units be able to clear enough water to prevent flooding? </p>
<p>When it comes to finding the best battery for your backup, BatteryClerk’s AJC Battery collection is all 12V and range in power from 75Ah to 100Ah. They’re also durable enough to be placed in areas where sump pumps typically reside and will keep the backup pump running at full capacity. <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/sump-pump-batteries">Browse our current collection.</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/jump-starter-replacement-batteries</id>
    <published>2018-12-10T13:36:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2019-04-08T03:30:28-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/jump-starter-replacement-batteries"/>
    <title>Jump Starter Replacement Batteries</title>
    <author>
      <name>Aric Shelko</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>A jump starter with a properly maintained battery can be the difference between sitting on the side of the road and making it to your destination. </p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/jump-starter-replacement-batteries">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Imagine you are on a dark street one evening and your car stalls. You try to start it and it becomes obvious that the battery is dead. More than a few horror movies start this way! You have no cell service and there is not another car in sight that might offer you a jump for your battery. What you need is a portable jump starter!</p>
<p>A portable jump starter or jump box is a battery with cables attached that allow you to jumpstart your car when the battery is dead. It’s safer and more convenient than jumping the battery with cables attached to another vehicle.  It does not charge your car battery, but provides the cranking power needed to start the engine. The car’s alternator then has the task of charging the battery as you drive.</p>
<p>Most jump starters are powered with a <span><a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/ajc-sealed-lead-acid-batteries">sealed lead acid battery</a></span>, and they come in various sizes so you can start engines of different sizes. Some come with additional features, like a small light, a USB port to charge portable devices and an air compressor to inflate flat tires.</p>
<p>The challenge with portable jump starters is that you don’t need it until you need it, so often they will be stowed in the trunk of a car until the car won’t start. The jump starter is retrieved and turned on, often completely dead itself from lack of use!</p>
<p><strong>Maintenance for a Portable Jump Starter</strong></p>
<p>To make sure this scenario does not happen to you, some preventative maintenance is in order. Sealed lead acid batteries self-discharge, meaning they will lose charge when sitting idle, for instance riding around in the trunk of your car.  In order for that battery to be ready to get your car back on the road, it needs to be charged regularly. Many portable jump starters have led lights that indicate if the battery is charged. So check the lights every month and especially before a long road trip. Follow the manufacturer’s instructions. The charge can take up to 5 hours depending on how low the charge was to start, and what size battery is in the unit.</p>
<p><strong>Replacing the Battery in a Portable Jump Starter</strong></p>
<p>If the battery has discharged past the point where it can be charged, you need to either replace the charger, or replace the battery. A quality replacement battery will allow you to get more years of service from the jump starter you already own.</p>
<p>Find a <span><a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/jump-starter-batteries">jump started replacement battery</a></span> that matches the size and voltage of your current battery. Once you have it, remove the cover of the portable jump started. Most models have screws that need to be removed to get to the battery, so a Philips head screw driver is needed. Note how the old battery is connected, disconnect it and connect the new battery. Replace the cover, and check that the new battery is charged and ready. If not, charge it, then replace it in the trunk of your car.</p>
<p>Keep in mind that batteries self-discharge more quickly when stored in high temperatures, like the trunk of your car in summer. Check the portable jump starter more often during the summer to make sure the battery is always charged and ready.</p>
<p>When it is time to replace that battery, you can be confident that BatteryClerk will have the size battery that you need to replace your jump starter battery, and that the quality replacement battery will provide you a safe and convenient way to start your car when and where you need it.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/differences-between-wet-cell-and-agm-batteries</id>
    <published>2018-08-22T10:58:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2019-04-08T04:15:17-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/differences-between-wet-cell-and-agm-batteries"/>
    <title>Differences between Wet Cell and AGM Batteries</title>
    <author>
      <name>Aric Shelko</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>AGM sealed lead acid batteries are ideal for powersports and other applications where vibrations and battery orientation might be a problem. </p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/differences-between-wet-cell-and-agm-batteries">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Lead acid batteries were invented in 1859 by Gaston Planté. They are the oldest type of rechargeable battery. They remain a good technology and the best option for many of our battery needs. While the basic chemistry has not changed, there have been a few improvements.</p>
<p>In the 1930's someone thought to add silica to the acid to create a gel instead of liquid inside the battery. Then in the 1970's, sealed versions of these batteries were produced. They were less dangerous and they could be installed in any orientation, not just upright. These are commonly referred to as gel batteries, or SLA for Sealed Lead Acid.</p>
<p>Another SLA improvement was introduced in the 1980's called <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/ajc-sealed-lead-acid-batteries" title="AJC Sealed Lead Acid Batteries">Absorbed Glass Mat batteries</a>. Developed originally for military aircraft, they are nearly immune to vibrations, making them suitable for all types of power sports equipment.</p>
<p><strong>Wet Cell (Flooded) Batteries</strong></p>
<p>The wet cell battery is closest to the original lead acid battery design and is still used in some applications. Some of the advantages of this type of battery are:</p>
<ul>
<li>that they have a long proven history of use</li>
<li>they are typically the best option for backup power for utilities and grid energy storage</li>
<li>they are more available worldwide</li>
<li>they have a longer deep cycle use than other batteries.</li>
</ul>
<p>Some of the downsides of these batteries include:</p>
<ul>
<li>that they must be used in an upright position because of the liquid inside</li>
<li>they are prone to damage from extreme weather conditions or from vibrations or forceful movement</li>
<li>they can be used only when ventilation is available</li>
<li>they are more dangerous due to the possibility of leaking the corrosive liquid that allows them to hold a charge.</li>
</ul>
<p>There are two types of wet cell battery. The maintenance free version comes filled and ready to charge; the serviceable one comes dry and must be filled before you use it and serviced during its lifetime.</p>
<p><strong>AGM Replacement Batteries</strong></p>
<p>This newer battery technology is more popular today than flooded wet cell batteries. Because they are smaller and can withstand motion, they are used for applications where wet cell batteries just won't work. Even though these batteries should be stored charged and are sensitive to being over charged, there are many benefits to using them.</p>
<p>Some of the benefits of AGM Replacement Batteries:</p>
<ul>
<li>they are slower to discharge than wet cell batteries</li>
<li>they are maintenance free, and arrive charged and ready to use</li>
<li>they are safer due to being sealed at the factory</li>
<li>they don't need to be installed in an upright position.</li>
</ul>
<p>AGM batteries are the ideal battery for power sports vehicles and other applications like <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/scooter-batteries" title="Mobility and Scooter batteries">wheel chairs and scooters</a> where vibrations and battery orientation could be issues.</p>
<p>If you need a replacement Sealed Lead Acid battery, BatteryClerk sells AGM batteries that will meet or exceed your vehicle's requirements. Check out our <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/sealed-lead-acid-batteries" title="Sealed Lead Acid batteres">Sealed Lead Acid batteries</a>. Keep it charged and ride on!</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/ups-rbc-replacement-batteries</id>
    <published>2018-07-03T15:21:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2019-04-08T03:53:19-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/ups-rbc-replacement-batteries"/>
    <title>UPS RBC Replacement Batteries</title>
    <author>
      <name>Aric Shelko</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[UPS, or uninterruptable power supply, is a necessity to protect your sensitive laptop, desktop or home theater equipment from power surges, and gives you a few minutes to shut your system down correctly. If you maintain the battery, you can extend the life of your UPS.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://batteryclerk.ca/blogs/news/ups-rbc-replacement-batteries">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>The PC that you depend on is plugged into the wall when the power goes out. All of your hard work immediately disappears. Learn about how to protect that important piece of technology.</p>
<p><strong>What is a UPS?</strong></p>
<p>UPS, or uninterruptable power supply, is a necessity in today's digital world. It protects your sensitive laptop, desktop or home theater equipment from power surges, and gives you a few minutes to shut your system down correctly when the power goes out or keeps it running long enough for the backup generator to take over.</p>
<p>These critical pieces of equipment sometimes end up in the landfill when they stop doing their job. Normal aging will cause all <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/ups-batteries">UPS batteries</a> to lose power. But you can extend the life of your UPS by replacing the battery regularly.</p>
<p><strong>Battery Environment</strong></p>
<p>The battery in your UPS will last longest when it is in an optimal environment. Don't place it near a heating vent, open window or where it will have sun shining on it. The area should be free of dust or moisture. Make sure the vents on the unit are not blocked so proper circulation is maintained. Keep the temperature in the not too hot, not too cold range with about 25<b>°</b>C being the optimal temperature.</p>
<p><strong>Maintain the Battery</strong></p>
<p>It is recommended that you perform maintenance on your UPS battery every 6 months to make sure they are still operating at their peak. Check to see if the battery case is bulging or bumpy. This might mean that the circuit in the battery that keeps it charged is set too high, or that the heat up and cool down cycles fluctuate too much. It you can, turn off the power and time how long the UPS keeps the equipment running. Reduced time indicates a battery near the end of its lifespan.</p>
<p>UPS Batteries can last between 3 and 4 years, depending on a variety of factors and the number of times it cycles for power outages. Replacing the battery before it fails provides that extra bit of insurance during hurricane or tornado season, or whatever season knocks out your power.</p>
<p><strong>Replace the Battery</strong></p>
<p>A good rule of thumb is to replace your battery when the warranty runs out. The battery is guaranteed to perform at its peak for that period of time. If the equipment you are protecting is important enough to warrant a UPS, it's important enough to have a battery that will handle the power outage.</p>
<p><a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/ups-batteries/brand_apc">UPS?á RBC battery replacements</a> do not require you to turn off the UPS or the equipment it is protecting to replace the battery. Most can be hot swapped with no damage or danger.</p>
<p><strong>How do I find the correct replacement battery?</strong></p>
<p>Find the model number on your UPC and plug it into the search on BatteryClerk.ca. We will provide you with all of the <a href="https://batteryclerk.ca/collections/ups-batteries">UPC replacement batteries</a> that will fit your device.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
